Guide to the Reynolds Price Papers, 1880-2014 RL.01050
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1946-2014, undated
  - Speeches and addresses, 1957-2007, undated
    - Liberating Journalism: Defining Reality Through Fiction, notes for Duke Fellows in Communication Policy program, 1976 Mar 18-20 (Box 235)
    - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, 1977 Jun 12-Jul 2 (Box 235)
    - Macon Methodist Church, homecoming, 1978 Sep 17 (Box 235)
    - Archibald Smith lecture, 1979 Apr (Box 235)
    - To the Chaired Professors, manuscript draft, 1979 Oct 15 (Box 235)
    - Joel Jackson's News, Weather, and Sports, draft comment, 1980 Oct 3 (Box 235)
    - Spender, Stephen, introduction for, 1981 Feb 2 (Box 235)
    - Anderson, Jeffrey, introduction for, Carrboro Art School, 1983 (Box 235)
    - Budd, Louis J., introduction for, 1984 Apr (Box 235)
    - Truths for Playwrights, Hendrix College, 1985 Oct 18 (Box 235)
    - National Book Critics Circle Award, acceptance speech (for Kate Vaiden), 1986 (Box 235)
    - Blackburn, William, commemoration of, homecoming weekend, 1988 Oct 21 (Box 235)
    - Welty, Eudora, eightieth birthday, 1989 Apr 9 (Box 235)
    - Pen-Faulkner reading, 1989 Oct 30 (Box 235)
    - Our Half of the Deal, Founder's Day, 1992 Dec 10 (Box 235)
    - Clear Pictures premiere (Charles Guggenheim documentary film), 1994 Mar 18 (Box 235)
    - Styron, William, introduction for, 1994 Nov (Box 235)
    - Another Thanks, 1994 (Box 235)
    - To the A.B. Duke Candidates, 1997 Apr 5 (Box 235)
    - Halloween readings, lists, 1998-2005 (Box 235)
    - Remarks at the awarding of a cookery prize to Ben and Karen Barker, Durham, 1998 Sep 13 (Box 235)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, introduction for, Duke University, 1999 Mar 26 (Box 235)
    - A Presentation to the North Caroliniana Society, 1999 Apr 9 (Box 235)
    - Letter to a Pair of Trinity College Freshman, as read to the Trinity College Board of Visitors, 1999 Apr 15 (Box 235)
    - Trinity College Board of Visitors, 1999; 1 Files 1 text file; 39 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
      Includes draft.
    - At an Unveiling, Duke University, 1999 Sep 30 (Box 235)
    - An Awful Gift and a Blindness: The Robert Penn Warren Lecture, Nashville, Oct 8, 1999 Oct 8 (Box 235)
    - A New Year's Greeting, James Taylor's Millenium Concert in the Raleigh Sports Arena, 1999 Dec 31-2000 Jan 1 (Box 235)
    - Donoghue, Denis, introduction for, 2001 Mar 6 (Box 236)
    - Donoghue, Denis, introduction for, 2001 Mar 6; 1 Files 1 MS Word file; 40 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - Malone, Michael, introduction for, 2001 Mar 8 (Box 236)
    - Malone, Michael, introduction for, 2001 Mar 8; 1 Files 1 MS Word file; 42 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - A Draft, 2001 (Box 236)
    - A Serious Way of Wondering, The Peabody Lecture, Harvard Memorial Church, 2001 Apr 21 (Box 236)
    - A Serious Way of Wondering - The Peabody Lecture, 2001 Apr 21; 1 Files 1 MS Word file; 129 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - In Long Measure, for W. D. Davies, 2001 May 24 (Box 236)
    - A Serious Way of Wondering, National Cathedral, Washington, D.C., 2001 Sep 26 (Box 236)
    - A Serious Way of Wondering, 2002 (Box 236)
    - Gospel for Mark, 2002, undated; 2 folders (Box 236)
    - Spencer Hielema, Mary Elizabeth, eulogy, 2003 Jan 7 (Box 236)
    - Keohane, Nan, remarks for a celebratory dinner, 2003 Oct 4 (Box 236)
    - Salt Lake City City Library, 2004 Apr (Box 236)
    - Faces From the Flood: Remembering Hurricane Floyd, voiceover script recorded by Price at WUNC-TV, 2004 Apr 12 (Box 236)
    - A Glad Welcome, Inauguration of Richard Brodhead, 2004 Sep (Box 236)
      Includes manuscript and typescript drafts with Price's annotations.
    - A Glad Welcome, introduction, 2004; 1 Files 1 MS Word file; 28 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - Duke: Past, Present and Future, 2004 Sep 18; 1 Files 1 MS Word file; 51 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - A Glad Welcome, Inauguration of Richard Brodhead, 2006 Jan 31 (Box 236)
    - Hijuelos, Oscar, introduction of, 2007 Feb 16 (Box 236)
    - According to Mark: Preface to a Reading, undated (Box 236)
    - According to Mark, undated (Box 236)
    - Capra, Frank, introduction of, undated (Box 236)
    - Dodging Apples, introduction to reading of, undated (Box 236)
    - Don Quixote, lecture, undated (Box 236)
    - Milton, John, poetry reading, introduction, undated (Box 236)
    - A Platonic Restaurant, undated (Box 236)
    - A Possible Adult Memoir, entitled Ardent Spirits, undated (Box 236)
    - Inaugural Poem, undated; 1 Files 1 MS Word file; 75 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - On Stephen Spender, undated (Box 236)
    - Porter, Joe Ashby, introduction, undated; 1 Files 1 MS Word file; 24 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - To a Convention of Writing Teachers, undated (Box 236)
    - Unpublishable Fiction, undated (Box 236)
    - Welty, Eudora: Celebration, undated (Box 236)
  - Audiovisual recordings of Price regarding writing, 1981-2000, undated
    This subseries includes recordings of Price discussing, reading, or performing his written materials and is arranged chronologically.
    - The Good News According to Mark, 1981 (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0102)
    - Family Album featuring Pat Conroy, Reynolds Price, Roy Blount Jr, 1996 (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0018)
    - James Dickey Sheep Child, 1996 Darren Wang (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0017)
    - Reynolds Price, 1996 Jan, Feb, Oct; 3 items (Box 290, Video-disc RL01050-DAT-0001 - RL01050-DAT-0004)
      Includes recordings For Art Silverman Halloween Show; For Margaret; and, commentaries.
    - All Things Considered recordings, 1996-2000; 10 items (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0005 - RL01059-CS-0014)
      Includes All Things Considered shows Death of a Friend from AIDS; Rehabilitation; Recent Letter from 1960 Student; MRI Time; 40th Anniversary of Teaching at Duke; teach Your Children Hope; Depression Suicide; and, Teaching Writing.
    - Reynolds Price, 1998 Sep 24 (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0004)
    - All Things Considered recordings, undated; 10 items (Box 291, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0028 - RL01050-CS-0037)
      Includes All Things Considered recordings Worship Privately Rather Than in a Church; Death Penalty; Death of a Friend from AIDS; Rehabilitation; Teaching (Recent Letter from 1960 Student; MRI Time; 40th Anniversary of Teaching at Duke; Teach Your Children Hope; Depression and Suicide; and, Teaching Writing.
    - All Things Considered recordings, undated; 10 items (Box 292, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0048 - RL01050-CS-0057)
    - A Writer's & Co., undated (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0021)
    - James Dickey - Sheep Child, undated; 2 items (Box 291, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0040, RL01050-CS-0059)
    - In Southern Words, Volume 2: Family Album, undated; 2 items (Box 291, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0041 - RL01050-CS-0042)
- Personal papers, 1880-2010, undated
  The Personal Papers Series is comprised of personal and family belongings; personal financial and medical documents; books from Price's personal library; family home movies; and, correspondence which was kept in a locked box in Price's home. This Series also includes audiovisual material of interviews with, and documentaries about Price; and, family, personal, and business photographs. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically, or chronologically, where this information is identified.
  All photographic safety and nitrate negatives are closed to use; copies are available on request. Nitrate negatives are scheduled for digitization. Please contact Rubenstein Library Research Services for assistance.
  - Audiovisual Materials Collected by Price, 1969-2005, undated
    This subseries includes audiovisual materials of and about, or of interest to Price. The materials are arranged chronologically.
    - Reynolds Price, John Cheever, 1969 Mar 4 (Box 290, Audio-reel RL01050-RR-0001)
    - Reynolds Price, John Cheever, 1969 Mar 4 (Box 290, Audio-reel RL01050-RR-0002)
    - Today, 1975 (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0001)
    - A Novelists View, Price, 1977 Nov (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0147)
    - Conversation, Eudora Welty & Price, 1978 Feb 25 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0123)
    - Chris Beebe & Price in Portland, Oregon, 1979 Dec 1 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0124)
    - Eudora Welty, 1982 Sep 16 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0126)
    - James Taylor & Price, Songs Without Words, 1989 Nov 15 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0153)
    - James Taylor & Price, Songs Without Words 2, 1989 Nov 16 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0142)
    - James Taylor premiere, Hymn, retirement of Bishop Paul Moore, St John the Divine, 1989 Jun 2 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0141)
    - James Taylor with Price at work, 1990 Mar 10 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0140)
    - Artifacts: Heard, Haxton, Price, 1990 May (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0004)
    - Price, Reynolds for Triquarterly, 1990 May 14 (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0003)
    - NC People, 1990 Jul 26 (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0018)
    - Trinity Church, NY, 1991 Nov (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0007)
    - New Hope Creek narrated by Reynolds Price, 1991 (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0008)
    - Reynolds Price at B.O., 1992 Jun 11 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0146)
    - Price, in Central Park, 1992 Sep 8 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0136)
    - The Ninth Van Cliburn International Piano Competition, A Life in New Music, 1993 Dec 15 (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0010)
    - Second Sunday Readings, 1994 Sep 11 (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0012)
    - Reynolds Price on Dateline, 1994 (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0011)
    - Ghost Stories, 1996 Oct 31 (Box 293, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0013)
    - Ghost Stories, 1996 Oct 31 (Box 298, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0036)
    - NC Bookwatch, 1998 May 29 (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0020)
    - Let Freedom Ring, 1999 (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0020)
    - Songs of Faith & Doubt, Mary Rocap, 2000 (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0154)
    - Threat Matrix, 2003 Sep 17 (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0021)
    - Threat Matrix, Episode 103 Dr. Germ, 2003 Sep 27 (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0022)
    - Massengill, David, 2003 (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CD-0008)
      The Christmas That Santy Claus Froze
    - Massengill, David, 2003 (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CD-0009)
      How I Chose a Life of Crime
    - Massengill, David, 2003 (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CD-0010)
      Morgana's Sleepover and the Witch's Hand
    - Faces From the Flood: Hurricane Floyd Remembered, 2004 (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0026)
      Price narrates the documentary.
    - Reynolds Price Papers Disk 1 Complete, 2005 Jul (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CD-0002)
    - Reynolds Price Papers Disk 1 Complete, 2005 Jul (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CD-0001)
    - 2nd Sunday Readings, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0023)
    - A Writer's Inheritance, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0026)
    - A Writer's Inheritance, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0004)
    - Artifacts, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0015)
    - Artifacts, Undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0017)
    - Bread on the Waters, undated (Box 290, Disk RL01050-CD-0003)
    - Bread on the Waters, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0027)
    - Bread on the Waters, undated (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0023)
    - Bread on the Waters Reynolds Price: Teacher, A Documentary by Wil Weldon, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0022)
    - Bread on the Waters Reynolds Price: Teacher, A Documentary by Wil Weldon, undated (Box 298, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0035)
    - Dateline, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0022)
    - Dateline, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0019)
    - Eudora Welty, TYW, undated (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0135)
    - Home movies, untitled, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0028)
    - Home movies, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0003)
    - Hymn, rehearsal, undated (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0138)
    - In Plane Sight, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0005)
    - James Taylor and Price, Hymn, undated (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0139)
    - Let Freedom Ring, undated (Box 295, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0002)
    - Let Freedom Ring, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0007)
    - New Hope Creek, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0018)
    - New Hope Creek, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0021)
    - New Testament Iterations and James' Addresses in Acts, Five Sermons, undated (Box 290, Audio-cassette RL01050-CD-0004)
    - NC Bookwatch, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0024)
    - North Carolina People, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0016)
    - NC People, duplicate, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0024)
    - NC People, duplicate, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0013)
    - NC People Reynolds Price, undated (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0026)
    - One Writer's Beginnings, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0010)
    - One Writer's Beginnings, undated (Box 296, Audio-cassette RL01050-Bcam-0010)
    - One Writer's Beginnings Symphony for Eudora's 80th, undated (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0027)
    - Reynolds Price, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0025)
    - Reynolds Price, undated (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0145)
    - Reynolds Price: A Short, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0008)
    - Reynolds Price: A Writer's Inheritance, undated (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0030)
    - Reynolds Price Charles Guggenheim narration, undated (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0148)
    - Price for Tri-Quarterly, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0016)
    - Reynolds Price for Triquarterly, undated (Box 295, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0006)
    - The Roots of Solitude, undated (Box 296, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0012)
    - The Roots of Solitude, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0011)
    - The Roots of Solitude: The Life and Work of Reynolds Price, undated (Box 294, Videotape RL01050-VHS-0019)
    - Second Sunday Readings, undated (Box 295, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0005)
    - The Threat Matrix, undated (Box 298, Dvd RL01050-DVD-0001)
    - Threat Matrix, Dr. Gem, undated (Box 295, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0003)
    - Threat Matrix, In Plain Sight, undated (Box 297, Videotape RL01050-Bcam-0021)
    - untitled, undated (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0143)
    - untitled, undated (Box 300, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0144)
    - Writers & Co: Reynolds Price, undated (Box 292, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0060)
  - Family and private papers, 1897-2009, undated
    This subseries contains family and personal belongings, and is arranged alphabetically.
    - Abraham Lincoln, certified hair, undated (Box 289)
    - Articles and clippings, 1907-2004, 2009, undated; 9 folders (Box 265)
      Includes magazine and newspaper clippings, and reprinted articles. Some items are annotated.
    - Art log, 2008 (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
      Identification of photographic images, Excel document
    - Artwork catalogs and photographs, 1991-2006, undated (Box 267)
    - Includes folders of inserts and items removed from books and folders including The Brilliance of Birds; Geraldine Farrar; Haiku for Carroll; Metaphysical Lyrics & Poems of the Seventeenth Century; Milton's God; Prayers Plainly Spoken; Selected Stories of Emily Dickinson; A Slow Moon; Surface of the Earth; Three Greek Romances; and, Women in Love., 1974-2008 (Box 266)
    - A Waiting Beauty, 2002 Nov (Box 266)
      Allure magazine article on Vivien Leigh by RP. Includes letter from Harriet Wasserman.
    - Awards, 2007-2008 (Box 266)
      Includes Breukelein Institute Gaudium award, and University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Thomas Wolf Lecture.
    - Awards and honorary degrees, 1991, 1996, 2003, 2009 (Box 338)
      Includes 45 Years at Duke and the Roberts Award for Literary Inspiration.
    - Birth announcement and baby book, 1933 (Box 266)
    - Blackburn, William, 1951 Jul (Box 266)
      Lady Magdalen Herbert and Her Son George (signed)
    - Bread on the Waters, undated (Box 266)
      Includes typescript drafts of Wilson Weldon's documentary on RP's life as a teacher.
    - Camp Sequoyah, 1953, 1957, 1993 (Box 266)
    - Certificate for North Carolina Award in Literature, 1997 (Box 168)
      Includes memorandum from North Carolina Deputy Secretary
    - Christmas gift lists, 1997, 1999-2000, 2002, 2004 (Box 266)
    - Day book of Mrs. William S. Price, 1940 (Box 266)
    - Degrees, Duke University and Merton College, Oxford, 1955, 1958 (Box 338)
      Includes Duke University and Merton College, Oxford; and honorary degree from UNC-CH
    - Diaries, 1897, 1985-2008 (Box 339)
      Includes the 1897 diary of Sallie B. Taylor, of Frenchtown, New Jersey.
    - Diaries and journals, 1957, 1960-1969, undated; 14 items (Box 340)
      Includes an undated address book.
    - Diaries and journals, 1970-1979, undated; 15 items (Box 341)
    - Diaries and journals, 1980-1988, 1991-1993, 2003, 2009; 12 items (Box 342)
    - The Dort Snort, 1959 Nov (Box 266)
      Includes a mockup of a newspaper using humorous news clippings and photographs.
    - Drawings, 1952-1960, undated (Box 266)
    - Drawings and Blueprints, 1939, undated (Box 350)
      Includes blue prints of RP's home
    - Duke Magazine for Alumni and Friends, 1986-1987, 1989 (Box 266)
      Includes Praising Price; and Love and Loss.
    - Duke: To Cross a Threshold, The Campaign for the Arts and Sciences, 1984 (Box 266)
    - Electronic documents, 2001, 2003, undated; 12 Files 12 MS Word and text files; 405 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
      Includes directions to Price's home; salary for Price's personal assistant; list of DVDs owned; a reading list; and, an email address book.
    - Envelope from Macmillan & Co., 1958-01-24 (Box 168)
    - Extracted articles and clippings from RP scrapbook, 1986-1993 (Box 266)
    - Fragments and notes, undated (Box 267)
    - Genealogy, undated; 2 folders (Box 267)
      Includes pedigree charts.
    - Genealogy, genetic history, 2005 (Box 267)
    - Genealogy, undated (Box 288)
      Pedigree charts of Grainger Walters, Mayfield, and Kendal families.
    - General system of punctuation, Reynold Price's, 2002 Oct (Box 267)
    - Gift lists for complimentary copies of his books, 1992-1998 (Box 267)
    - High school notes, 1949, undated (Box 267)
      Includes notes on RP's wardrobe, and class schedules.
    - Kaufman, Wallace, 1962 (Box 267)
      Poems (manuscript, includes notes removed from book)
    - Lance, quote, undated (Box 267)
      And you, quiet smile on your face; serene giver.
    - Merton College, 1955-1956, 2005, undated (Box 267)
      Includes Merton College calendars.
    - Mexico, Yucatan travel map, annotated, undated (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Mind Roams Free, The, 1994 May (Box 267)
      Time magazine article by William A. Henry III. Includes letter from Harlan J. Berk.
    - Miscellaneous information and notes about writing and career, 1995-2003, undated (Box 267)
    - Miscellany, 1927-2003, undated (Box 267)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1937-1993; 6 folders (Box 210)
      Includes articles about authors, Duke Students, RP, local North Carolina News
    - Oxford University, 1953-1955, undated (Box 267)
      Includes Liberal Club; Russell & Palmerston Club; Liberal Party Group; and, Cosmos and United Nations Club term pamphlets.
    - Personal itineraries for book tours, readings, and other events, 1971-2005, undated; 2 folders (Box 268)
    - Personal itinerary for visit to the Memorial Church, Harvard University, 2001 Apr 20-23 (Box 268)
    - Phi Delta Theta Fraternity paddle, signed by members, 1953 (Box 276)
    - Pine View School for the Gifted book for Reynolds Price, 2008 Mar 25 (Box 268)
    - Postcard collection, 1949-1984, undated (Box 275)
      Includes postcards of art, celebrities, and geographic locations.
    - Press pass, Time magazine, 1977 Jan 20 (Box 268)
    - Price biographical essay, undated (Box 268)
      Includes handwritten manuscripts of a biographical essay.
    - Price passports, 1955-1994 (Box 268)
    - Price war ration book, 1942 (Box 268)
    - Reconciling United Methodists and Friends of North Carolina newsletters, 2001, 2003-2004, undated (Box 268)
    - Rodwello, Elizabeth - Seaboard ticket, 1926 (Box 268)
    - Sculpture Receipts and Description, 1988-2007 (Box 268)
    - Sketchbook, 1977-1980 (Box 268)
    - Statements made at ceremonies for friends, including banquets, funerals, and weddings, 1996-2003 (Box 268)
    - Taylor, James, RP letter to, with lyrics, 1990 Feb 19 (Box 268)
    - The Times Literary Supplement, 1958-12-12 (Box 168)
    - Transcript of Bill Moyers' Journal: Carter and Country, 1979 (Box 268)
    - Travel documents, 1955-1956, undated (Box 268)
    - Travel documents, 1970-1979 (Oversize-folder 2)
      Map of Mexico and Yucatan trip.
    - Unsigned drawing, undated (Box 268)
    - Vivien Leigh and Laurence Oliver in Caesar and Cleopatra (Shaw, Bernard), Laurence Olivier Productions, 1974 (Box 268)
      Miller, Gilbert (inscribed)
    - William Price article, by Deborah Norman, undated (Box 268)
  - Financial, legal, health records, 1949-2007, undated
    Includes personal family, financial, and medical records, arranged alphabetically.
    - Art Collection, 1997-2005, undated; 3 folders (Box 274)
      Includes documentation, authentications, and receipts for items in RP's art collection.
    - Art log, undated; 1 Files Excel document; 21 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
    - Duke Library manuscripts documents, 1972-2005 (Box 274)
      Includes documentation of manuscripts transferred to Special Collections.
    - Medical records, 1955-2005, undated (Box 273)
      Includes A Day in the Life caretaker instructions; and, voice exercises.
    - Publishing agreements and contracts, 1957-2004, undated; 3 folders (Box 270)
    - Rare book purchases, 1976-1999 (Box 274)
      includes documentation, authentications, and receipts for items in Price's rare book collection.
    - Royalty statements, 1962-1984, 1992-2004; 6 folders (Box 270)
    - Royalty statements, 2003-2007; 2 folders (Box 270)
    - Tax records, 1964-1979; 21 folders (Box 271)
    - Tax records, 1980-1984; 13 folders (Box 272)
    - Tax records, 1985-2004; 9 folders (Box 273)
    - William S. and Elizabeth Price, check books, 1954-1965 (Box 273)
    - William S. and Elizabeth Price Home, 1939-1969, undated (Box 273)
    - Electronic documents, 1992, 2000-2005, undated; 28 Files 28 MS Word and text files; 830 KB (Digital-materials RL01050-SET-0001)
      Includes lists of personal assistants and job descriptions and agreements; correspondence with tax preparer and W-2 information; Price's of people to notify upon his death, and possible executors; and, correspondence with physicians and assistants.
  - Home library, 1924-2010
    Many of the volumes in the Home Library subseries have been signed by the authors, or inscribed to Price. They are arranged alphabetically by author, and occasionally by title.
    - Aiken, Conrad, 1948 (Box 238)
      Selected Poems of Emily Dickinson
    - Allison Jr., Dale C., 2005 (Box 239)
      Resurrecting Jesus
    - An Anthology of Modern Japanese Poetry, 1957 (Box 239)
      Includes undated note about the poems, with no signature.
    - Anderson, Carl L., George W. Williams, 1959 (Box 261)
      British and American Essays, 1950-1956
    - Archive, The, Vol. 88 No. 2; Vol 108 No. 1, 1975 Fall, 1996 Spring; 2 items (Box 261)
      Duke University undergraduate creative-writing publication
    - Atlantic, The, Vol. 167, No. 2, 1941 Feb (Box 261)
      The Atlantic, Vol. 167, No. 2, Feb 1941